Guide to the United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia Records - Addendum F
Yale University Divinity School Library
United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia Records - Addendum F
1974-2001
RG 11F
Yale University Divinity School Library
8
(16 boxes)
This record group represents a continuation of the official archives of the United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia, supplementing and overlapping the papers in record groups 11, 11A, 11B, 11C, 11D, and 11E. It provides extensive information about the institutions and projects to which the United Board lent its support. The United Board was established to support and coordinate the activities of Protestant colleges and universities in China. Following the Communist takeover of China, the United Board focused its efforts on educational work in other Asian nations. In recent years it has re-focused some of its activities on China.
United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the UBCHEA.
Biographical / Historical
Detailed information about the work of the United Board for Christian Higher Education during the earlier portion of the period represented by these archives is contained in Paul Lauby's book Sailing on Winds of Change: Two Decades in the Life of the United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia, 1969-1990.
Scope and Contents
I. Organization and Policy Records
II. General Files
III. China Programs
V. Financial Records
The files have been maintained as sent by the United Board.
Arrangement
I. Organization and Policy Records
II. General Files
III. China Programs
V. Financial Records
Religious education -- Asia; Universities and colleges -- China; Educators; United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia
- Organization and Policy Records, 1985; Series I
  - Board Restructuring, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Three Year Support program, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Task Force on Staffing and organization, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Directions for the 80s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Directions for the 90s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Asian Trustees Consultation Philippines, Oct 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Asian Trustees Consultation Philippines, Oct 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - China Concerns Sub-Committee, Jul1978-Jun1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - China Concerns Sub-Committee, Jul 1979-Jun1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - China Concerns Sub-Committee, Jul 1980-Jun 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - China Concerns Sub-Committee, Jul 198l-Jun 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - China Concerns Sub-Committee, Jul 1982-Jun 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - China Concerns Sub-Committee Minutes/Agendas, Jul 1988-Jun 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - China Concerns Sub-Committee Correspondence, 1988-91 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - China Sub-Committee on Library and Translation Programs, Jul 1979-Jun 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - China Sub-Committee on Library and translation programs, Jul 1980-Jun 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Committee on North American based China programs, Jul 1980-Jun 1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Social Responsibility for Investment: Committee on Minutes, etc., 1992-93 FY (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - University Programs Sub-Committee Minutes, Agendas, Correspondences, etc., 1990-92 FY (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Women's Concerns Committee, 1992-94 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- General Files, 1994; Series II
  - Aldritt, Dr. Les; Visiting professor to India Summer, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - APECA Association of Psychological and Educational Counselors of Asia (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Reports Asia/NA, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Asian Women's Institute Lahore, Pakistan Correspondence, Sep 1986-1994 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Association of Christian Universities and Colleges in Asia (ACUCA): Proposals /Grants, 1990/91-1993/94 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bates, Dr. Robert S. UB Trustee Christian Church (Disciples of Christ) Representative Correspondence, 1984-93 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Byrnes, Mr. and Mrs. Danfond: Silliman University (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Calvary United Protestant Church Park Forest, Illinois: Supports Silliman Correspondence, 1980-93 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Cann, Jenkins: Amity Foundation (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Chautauqua Institution (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Dr. Julia Ching University of Toronto UB Trustee Correspondence from, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Fetter, Andrew Hue teachers Trng. Vietnam (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Fisher, Dr. and Mrs. Edwin O. UB Donor and United Methodist Church Representative (deceased Dec.21, 2001). Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Hessel, Dr. and Mrs. L.W. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Kacoroski, Rosemary: Correspondence, 1991-94 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Kao Cheng-Shu Trustee (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Karlen, Robert: Sichuan Conservatory of Music, 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Kauffman, Suzanne: Vietnam Teacher, 1993-94 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Lake, Dr. Mary Beth, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Long, James B: Petra University (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Lutz, Dr. Jessie: Correspondence, 1991-94 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Mack, Margaret Correspondence, 1984-88 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - McIntosh, Peggy (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Amity Foundation: Moy, Ms. Elaine, 1992-94 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Neumeier, Edward and Gloria: Hue Teacher's Training College, 1986-94 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Nyi, Mr. and Mrs. Henry (Gloria) Ginting Girls Middle School Scholarship Fund Sponsors (deceased) Correspondence, 1980-97 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Park, Dr. Eun-Koo and Kim, Mrs. Sung Hee Visiting Professors for 88-89 (from Soong Sil University) Correspondence, 1987- (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Peterson, Gladys Ms. Trustee (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Pusey, Dr. Nathan M. (Was 1979/83 President of UB) Correspondence, 1983- (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Pusey, Dr. Nathan M. (UBCHEA President 1979-1983) Correspondence, 1980-82 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Rockefeller, M/Mary Laurance S. UB Donors Correspondence, 1980- (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Ruiz family pledges (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Sawin, Dr. Margaret M. Correspondence, etc., 1989- (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Seymour, Susan (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Saba, Shoichi Mr. UB Trustee, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Silliman, Dr. Robert B. Correspondence, 1980-88 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Sovik, Ruth Mrs. UB Trustee (deceased Jan. 1, 2000), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Sovik, Dr. Arne B. Switzerland Correspondence, 1980-99 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Spiegel, Dr. Hans B.C. (Eleanor) Correspondence, 1982-94 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Silliman, Mr. Stanley UB Trustee Correspondence, 1980-95 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Stowe, Dr. David M (deceased Jan. 10, 2000) Correspondence, 1980- (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Sutarno, Dr. UB Trustee Correspondence, Jan 1986-95 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Talley, Mrs. Madelon DeVoe UB Trustee Correspondence, 1980-97 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Tan, Dr. Charlotte T.C. UB Trustee Correspondence, 1980-99 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Tanis, Mrs. Elaine B. UB Trustee, 1989-96 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Taylor, Arthur B. UB Trustee, 1994-95 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Thelin, Dr. and Mrs. Mark (Virginia) Auburndale, Mass. Correspondence, 1980-95 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Thiel, Eric: Vietnam, 1994-95 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Thurber, Dr. L. Newton Presbyterian Church Representative on UB Trustees Correspondence, 1980-88 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Tye, Dr. and Mrs. Norwood (Wilma) Correspondence, 1980-93 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Vieg, Dr. and Mrs. John A. (Elizabeth) Claremont, California Correspondence, 1980-94 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Walcott, Dr. Ronald visiting professor to Silliman University, 1987-95 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Wade, Dr. Donald V. UB Trustee Representative for Presbyterian Church in Canada Correspondence, 1980-97 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Williamson, Jr. Mr. Malcolm R. UB Trustee Correspondence, 1983-92 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Weter, Miss Winifred E. Seattle, Washington Correspondence, 1980-97 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Woo, Mr. Franklin J. China Program Director NCCC/USA UB Trustee Correspondence, 1980-96 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Wang, Dr/Mrs. S.C. (Mamie) Tenalfly, N.J. UB Donors Correspondence, 1980-95 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - White, Rev. Haydn O. UB Trustee Representative Presbyterian Church Correspondence, 1980-95 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - U.S. Government Aid De La Salle University Proposal Aid/Asha, 1976-77 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Aid - Satya Wacana Proposal Administration building Aid/Asha, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Educational Management Consultancy Workshop held at Hong Kong Baptist College, Apr 1976 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Harvard-Yenching Institute meeting of the trustees, -1979 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Harvard-Yenching Institute meeting of the trustees, -1979 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Silliman University Library Proposal, 1974-77 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Silliman University Library Proposal, 1974-77 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Silliman - Specifications for new library project. Agreement for the construction for the new library, Sep 1977 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Silliman University Library Proposal (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Silliman University Library Proposal final estimates - including equipment and furniture, Oct 1977 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Aid/Asha Grant # 173 Yonsei University Library. Project completed, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 92)
- China Programs and Institutions, Series III
  - Visiting Scholars Program
    - Cheng, Xian-Fu - to Silliman from Anhui Normal University, 1989-94 (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - Chen, Xinjie (Mr.) CUHK - Huazhong Normal, 1989-94 (Box 9, Folder 94)
    - Cheng Xiao-Ming - Anhui Institute of Technology (Box 9, Folder 95)
    - Cheng Zijuan - Northeast Normal University, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 96)
    - Deng, Ms. Ying, China: Davis and Elkins College, West Virginia, 1992-93 (Box 9, Folder 97)
    - Dong, Ya-Fen - Pacific Lutheran University - Fudan University, 1992-93 (Box 9, Folder 98)
    - Hanwen, Fang - Shaanxi Teachers University, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - He, Lan - Huazhong University, 1992-93 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Hu, Mr. Shiguang visiting scholar Correspondence, 1984- (Box 9, Folder 101)
    - Hua Hui-Fang Suzhou University - McPherson College, KS, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Huang, Ms. Ching-Feng -Nanjing - King College, Bristol, TN, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - Huang, Ji-Ying Alma College Alma, MI, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - Huang Shijian - Hangzhou University, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Huang Yan - Zhengzhou University, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Jin Rungui - East China University Hood College, MD, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Kong Xiangjun - University Hawaii, 1992-93 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Lee, Prof. (Ms.) Jingai Yanbian - Queens College, Charlotte, NC, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Li Chengmei - Yanbian University, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - Li, He: Beijing - Hiram College (Hiram, OH), 1992-94; 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - Lin Han - Huanan Women's College, 1992-94 (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - Nie Jiongiang - Suzhou University, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - Qian, Xingrong- Nanjing Whitworth (Spokane), 1992 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Qiu Zhenggui - Sichuan Conservatory of Music, 1993-94 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Shao, Qing-Yu (Mr.) Huazhong - Augustana College, IL, 1991-93 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Shi Jinchuan - Hangzhou University:, 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 117)
    - Sun, Margaret - Xinjiang University, 1985-2001 (Box 10, Folder 118)
    - Tu, Pei - Millikin University, 1991-93 (Box 10, Folder 119)
    - Siping T.C., Jilin Wang, Jun (Ms.) - University of Iowa, 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 120)
    - Wang, Tingzhi - Sichuan University - Stanford, Univ., California, 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 121)
    - Wang, Yidan - Suny, Buffalo, NY - NE China Normal, 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 122)
    - Xu, Regian (Mr.) University of Colorado - Nanjing Normal, 1993-95 (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Zhong, Yang - Northeast Normal University, 1992-94 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - Yu Chengxuan - Sichuan University, 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Zhang Hue - Huanan Women's College, 1992-94 (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Zhing Ming - Beijing Foreign Studies University, 1992-94 (Box 10, Folder 127)
    - Zhu Mingquan - Fudan University - Emory University, GA, 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 128)
    - Mather - Shenyang Conservatory of Music (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Universities and Institutions
    - Amity Foundation - Correspondence/Grants, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - Amity - Institute for Social Development Training, 1989-92 (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - Amity - Women's Health Education Project, 1990-93 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - Beijing Foreign Studies University Correspondence, 1992-93 (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Capital Normal University: Correspondence, 1992-94 (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - Central Conservatory of Music Beijing, 1987-94 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    - Center for U.S-China Arts Exchange, 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 136)
    - Huazhong: Central China Normal University Proposals/Grants, 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 137)
    - Huazhong: Central hina Normal University: General Correspondence, 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 138)
    - CEAIE: Proposals/Grants, 1992-94 (Box 11, Folder 139)
    - East China Normal University General Correspondence, 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 140)
    - East China Normal University General Correspondence, 1991-93 (Box 11, Folder 141)
    - Fudan University General Correspondence, 1990-93 (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - Fudan University Correspondence, 1988-89 (Box 11, Folder 143)
    - Foundation for Books to China San Francisco: Executive Dir.: Dale Bratton Correspondence, 1980-93 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - China Fujian Teachers University General Correspondence, 1988-91 (Box 12, Folder 145)
    - Ginling College, 1993-94 (Box 12, Folder 146)
    - Hangzhou University: Grants/Proposals Correspondence, 1992-93 (Box 12, Folder 147)
    - Hwa Nan Professional College for Women Correspondence, 1992-94 (Box 12, Folder 148)
    - China Institute for Development Training, 1993-94 (Box 12, Folder 149)
    - International Crane Foundation, 1981-91 (Box 12, Folder 150)
    - Jiangsu Institute of Education, 1988-93 (Box 12, Folder 151)
    - China MA - MAZ, 1988-93 (Box 12, Folder 152)
    - Nanjing Colloquium: China: Dr. Roger Johnson, 1988-93 (Box 12, Folder 153)
    - Nanjing Normal University: Project Proposals/Grants, 1993-94 (Box 12, Folder 154)
    - Nanjing Normal University Correspondence, 1991-95 (Box 12, Folder 155)
    - Nanjing Normal University, 1992-98 (Box 13, Folder 156)
    - Nanjing University: Proposals/Grants, 1993-94 (Box 13, Folder 157)
    - Nanjing University: College English Teachers Training Program, 1993-94 (Box 13, Folder 158)
    - Nanjing University: Cett materials, 1993-95 (Box 13, Folder 159)
    - China: National Committee on United States-China Relations, Inc. NYC Arthur Rosen, President, 1992-93 (Box 13, Folder 160)
    - China: Princeton; Summer Seminars in China Program, 1988-92 (Box 13, Folder 161)
    - Shaanxi Teachers University: Correspondence, 1993-94 (Box 13, Folder 162)
    - Shaanxi Teachers University: Proposals/Grants Library project, 1992-94 (Box 13, Folder 163)
    - Shaanxi Teachers University Correspondence, 1992-93 (Box 13, Folder 164)
    - Sichuan Conservatory of Music: Correspondence, 1990-94 (Box 14, Folder 165)
    - International Symposium US in Developing countries (Sichuan), 1993-94 (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - Sichuan University Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 14, Folder 167)
    - Correspondence, 1983-94 (Box 14, Folder 168)
    - China: University of Inner Mongolia, 1987-93 (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - China: UCLA Library Delegation, 1993-94 (Box 14, Folder 170)
    - Xiamen University: Proposals/Grants, 1993-94 (Box 14, Folder 171)
    - Yanbian University: Project Report, 1993-94 (Box 14, Folder 172)
    - Zhengzhou University Correspondence, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 173)
    - Zhengzhou University Women's Oral History Project, 1992-94 (Box 15, Folder 174)
- Financial Records, 1981-83; Series IV
  - Finance and Administration Committee, 1981-83 (Box 15, Folder 175)
  - Finance and Administration Committee, 1983-84 (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - Finance and Administration Committee, 1984-86 (Box 15, Folder 177)
  - Finance and Administration Committee, 1986-88 (Box 15, Folder 178)
  - Finance and Administration Committee, 1988-89 (Box 15, Folder 179)
  - Finance and Administration Committee, 1989-91 (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1980-81 (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1980-81 (Box 15, Folder 182)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1981-82 (Box 16, Folder 183)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1982-83 (Box 16, Folder 184)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1983-84 (Box 16, Folder 185)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1983-84 (Box 16, Folder 186)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1984-85 (Box 16, Folder 187)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1984-85 (Box 16, Folder 188)
  - Investment and Banking Committee, 1985-88 (Box 16, Folder 189)
  - Investment Committee, 1988-93 (Box 16, Folder 190)